Horia Delicoti

About Me

Passionate DevOps Engineer with 7+ years of experience in automation, Linux, and system reliability. I specialise in automating processes, improving infrastructure efficiency, and implementing security policies. Certified in Terraform and System Administration, I seek to learn, grow, and stay updated with the latest DevOps tools and best practices.

Technologies _

Operating System: Linux (open-source), CentOS, Ubuntu CI/CD Tools: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Git

Languages: Python, Bash, Ruby **Monitoring:** Grafana, Prometheus, AppDynamics, Splunk

Infrastructure as Code: Ansible, Puppet, Terraform **Containerization:** Docker, KVM, Kubernetes

Networking: DNS, SSL, HTTPS, Firewall, TCP/IP **Cloud:** AWS, GCP

Experience _____

Web Developer | Info Grup 🗹

Jan 2024 - Present

- Developed and launched website using HTML, CSS, and WordPress
- Created a plan for the website downtime, ensuring 99.9% uptime through performance monitoring (response time, error rates), alerts, regular maintenance schedules, failover strategies, load balancing configurations, and redundancy measures to minimize disruptions and increase reliability
- Improved the website design and reduced response time by 30%, improving user experience and performance through caching, image compression, and CDN
- Optimized page load speed by over 40%, reducing load time through caching and optimizing CSS and HTML file sizes

DevOps Engineer | Deloitte Digital **☑**

Nov 2021 - Aug 2023

- Automated performance report generation by integrating Python scripts into the Jenkins pipeline, reducing processing time by 99% while improving data accuracy and reliability
- Deployed, configured, and maintained 1 monitoring and alerting system, ensuring 24/7 system visibility. Set up 50+ custom alerts for performance metrics, reducing incident response time by 40%
- Identified and resolved 100+ technical issues by utilizing logs, performance metrics, and diagnostic tools, reducing recurring problems by 60%. These improvements increased system uptime from 99.5% to 99.9%
- Used Ansible to automate deployment, security configurations, maintenance tasks, and server administration

Infrastructure Engineer | Bitdefender 🗹

Nov 2019 - Oct 2021

- Optimized Puppet server performance by improving server configuration, resource allocation, and JVM settings, reducing response time from 3 minutes to 30 seconds while efficiently managing 2,000 production servers
- Managed server administration tasks, including user/group management, permissions, and firewall configuration
- · Analyzing logs and optimizing resource consumption to ensure system efficiency and security
- Developed automation tools script to improve system deployments
- · Monitoring systems health to address software or server issues on bare metal and VM machines
- Maintained system uptime of 99.9% by generating, configuring, and installing SSL certificates for 15+ designated systems, ensuring seamless installation through Puppet across all monitored environments

QA Engineer | Balena LTD 🗹

Jul 2016 - Nov 2019

- Designed a testing framework for evaluating boot methods, onboard peripherals, and OS features of SBCs, using Docker to spawn parallel test environments. This enabled simultaneous board testing, reducing iteration times by 70%, accelerating the overall testing process, and improving product reliability
- Created and documented test cases to ensure product compliance with specifications, improving test coverage and getting accurate validation of product features

Education _____

Computer Science and Engineering Programme | University Politehnica of Bucharest ☑

2009 - 2013

• Major: Automatic Control and Computer Faculty

Information Technology and Mathematics | Dunarea ☑

2005 - 2009

• Achievements: Physics Olympiad | Stefan Procopiu 🗹

Certificates _____

LFCS: Linux Foundation Certified Systems Administrator ☑ | The Linux Foundation ☑

Issued July 2024

Terraform Associate (003) ☑ | HashiCorp ☑

Issued June 2023

Projects _____

Home Infrastructure | github.com/horia-delicoti/infrastructure ☑

• A collection of Ansible playbooks to automate and optimize home infrastructure, including server configuration, monitoring, alerting, Docker, and more. All playbooks run within Docker containers, ensuring consistent and isolated environments with a focus on efficiency and scalability

Deploy Web Application in AWS using Terraform | github.com/horia-delicoti/get-started_aws **∠**

 A set of Terraform scripts to provision, modify, and destroy AWS infrastructure, enabling efficient management of cloud resources